<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Features on Manjaro Linux - enjoy the simplicity</title>
    <link>https://rumangerst.github.io/homepage/public/features/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Features on Manjaro Linux - enjoy the simplicity</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 00:36:21 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rumangerst.github.io/homepage/public/features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Configured with one click</title>
      <link>https://rumangerst.github.io/homepage/public/features/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 00:36:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rumangerst.github.io/homepage/public/features/tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Manjaro comes with it&amp;rsquo;s own tools that help you configuring your computer the way you want - without searching for scattered settings across the whole system and looking things up on the internet. Just open the system control panel, open the tool and select what you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section id=&#34;pamac&#34; &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;feature-screenshot-fan&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;;baseurl;/img/applications/manjaro_pamac.png&#34;/&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Choose, install, finished!&lt;/h3&gt;
    Manjaro maintains it&#39;s own program to install, update and remove packages from the system. Just open it, choose what you want and click &#39;install&#39;. All other needed things will be done automatically and the only thing you need to do is to start the program.
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&#34;locale&#34; &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;feature-screenshot-fan&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div &gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Manjaro speaks my language&lt;/h3&gt;
    If you don&#39;t speak english, it&#39;s no problem for Manjaro. Just start our locale settings and select the language you want. After you logged out and in again, everything is exactly the way you want. We also offer you a special tool that automatically installs language packs for a variety of programs and notifies you if you can get translation sfor your favorite programs.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;;baseurl;/img/applications/manjaro_locale.png&#34;/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&#34;mhwd&#34; &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;feature-screenshot-fan&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;;baseurl;/img/applications/manjaro_mhwd.png&#34;/&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;New graphics card? One click and it&#39;s done&lt;/h3&gt;
    Manjaro comes with MHWD, the Manjaro Hardware Detection. If you need drivers for your hardware, just open it, click on &#34;Auto Install&#34; and wait until it&#39;s finished. That&#39;s it.
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&#34;timeanddate&#34; &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;feature-screenshot-fan&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Traveling a lot?&lt;/h3&gt;
    If you need to change the timezone, because you are on holiday or you need to travel for your business, we provide you a handy tool to quickly switch the time settings to have more time to get things done or enjoy the free time.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;;baseurl;/img/applications/manjaro_locale.png&#34;/&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&#34;useraccounts&#34; &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;feature-screenshot-fan&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;;baseurl;/img/applications/manjaro_useraccounts.png&#34;/&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Divide and conquer&lt;/h3&gt;
    If multiple people use your computer, just create an account for each of them. So everybody can have their own data and own privileges what they can and can&#39;t do.
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&#34;kernel&#34; &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;feature-screenshot-fan&#34;&gt;

    &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Switch the core with one click&lt;/h3&gt;
    Power-users and people who need special features of the Linux Kernel that don&#39;t come with the default one can just switch to a different Kernel with one click. Do you make music or need other realtime features? Just switch to a RT-Kernel. Do you need the newest improved open-source graphics drivers? Just switch to a newer one. Manjaro let&#39;s you not only switch to another Kernel, but supports multiple installed kernels at the same time. Just re-boot your system and you can just switch between all installed Kernels in the boot menu.
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;img src=&#34;;baseurl;/img/applications/manjaro_kernels.png&#34;/&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scientists</title>
      <link>https://rumangerst.github.io/homepage/public/features/usercases/scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 15:08:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rumangerst.github.io/homepage/public/features/usercases/scientists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Manjaro&amp;rsquo;s repositories contain the newest available versions of popular software like the statistic language &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.r-project.org/&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt;, the numerical computational package &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scilab.org/&#34;&gt;Scilab&lt;/a&gt;, and the scripting language &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org/&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; and more. Also &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latex-project.org/&#34;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt;, additional packages for it and software like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lyx.org/&#34;&gt;Lyx&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.texstudio.org/&#34;&gt;TeXstudio&lt;/a&gt; is readily available and can be installed with just few clicks. With LaTeX scientists can create high-quality documents and presentations with included math-forumulas, chemical molecules, self-updating cross- and literature references and more without being restrained by a specific style or document type. Lyx encapsulates LaTeX in a friendly GUI for people who don&amp;rsquo;t have much experience with LaTeX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional modules for R, Python, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.perl.org/&#34;&gt;Perl&lt;/a&gt; and others are either available directly through Manjaro&amp;rsquo;s repositories or can be compiled and installed with programs like &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/pip&#34;&gt;pip&lt;/a&gt; or the integrated package management of R.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No additional software is need as all needed build-tools are pre-installed. Experimental data can be analyzed with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kde.org/applications/education/labplot/&#34;&gt;LabPlot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The repositories are extended further by the Arch User Repository (AUR), that contains build-scripts that generate packages. Included is &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Yaourt&#34;&gt;Yaourt&lt;/a&gt; that handles the building, installing and updating of AUR-packages with an easy-to-use command line interface. Software available in the AUR are for example &lt;a href=&#34;https://software.intel.com/en-us/intel-mkl&#34;&gt;popular libraries&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://software.intel.com/en-us/intel-compilers&#34;&gt;compilers&lt;/a&gt;, tools for bioinformatics like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tbi.univie.ac.at/RNA/&#34;&gt;Vienna RNA&lt;/a&gt; package or IDE like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;R-Studio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gamers</title>
      <link>https://rumangerst.github.io/homepage/public/features/usercases/gamers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 15:08:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rumangerst.github.io/homepage/public/features/usercases/gamers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Manjaro comes preinstalled with &lt;a href=&#34;https://steampowered.com&#34;&gt;Steam&lt;/a&gt;, so there&amp;rsquo;s no need to go to a website and download it manually. Installing drivers, updates and more applications is handled through the package manager and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.manjaro.org/index.php/Manjaro_Hardware_Detection&#34;&gt;Manjaro Hardware Detection Tool&lt;/a&gt; that will do all operations in just a couple of minutes and never requires or forces a restart of the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the design of Linux, hardware like Gamepads are recognized instantaneously if drivers are available, so users don&amp;rsquo;t have to wait until it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Included in the package repositories is software like &lt;a href=&#34;http://teamspeak.com/&#34;&gt;Teamspeak 3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mumble.info/&#34;&gt;Mumble&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.skype.com/&#34;&gt;Skype&lt;/a&gt;. Games like the strategy game &lt;a href=&#34;http://play0ad.com/&#34;&gt;0 A.D.&lt;/a&gt; or the sandbox-game &lt;a href=&#34;https://minecraft.net/&#34;&gt;Minecraft&lt;/a&gt;, including mods and custom launchers like &lt;a href=&#34;http://multimc.org/&#34;&gt;MultiMC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://feed-the-beast.com/&#34;&gt;Feed the Beast&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mcedit.net/&#34;&gt;MCEdit&lt;/a&gt; are directly available via Manjaro&amp;rsquo;s repositories or the Arch User Repository (AUR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For people who want to play old games or games from different platforms or operating systems, the latest versions of emulators or runtimes like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dosbox.com/&#34;&gt;Doxbox&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dolphin-emulator.com/&#34;&gt;Dolphin&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.winehq.org/&#34;&gt;WINE&lt;/a&gt; are also available in the package repositories and can be installed with just a few clicks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>students</title>
      <link>https://rumangerst.github.io/homepage/public/features/usercases/students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 15:08:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rumangerst.github.io/homepage/public/features/usercases/students/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Manjaro&amp;rsquo;s repository of free and quality software is filled with programs for each subject. For mathematics, simple to advanced calculations can be done using scientific calculators like &lt;a href=&#34;https://qalculate.github.io/&#34;&gt;Qalculate!&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.speedcrunch.org/&#34;&gt;SpeedCrunch&lt;/a&gt; that don&amp;rsquo;t copy the experience of most hardware-calculators, but allow free editing of functions and terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more complex mathematics, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scilab.org/&#34;&gt;Scilab&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://andrejv.github.io/wxmaxima/&#34;&gt;WxMaxima&lt;/a&gt; will handle advanced numeric and algebraic tasks. Teachers love &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.geogebra.org/&#34;&gt;Geogebra&lt;/a&gt; to show physics, trigonometry, vector operations and more due to the easy-to-use graphical editing of mathematical relations, plotting of functions and setting constraints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Physics including molecular dynamics, gravitation and coloumb forces and more can be taught using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kde.org/applications/education/step/&#34;&gt;Step&lt;/a&gt;. The earth can be explored with &lt;a href=&#34;https://marble.kde.org/&#34;&gt;Marble&lt;/a&gt;, while the sky and stars can be viewed with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stellarium.org/&#34;&gt;Stellarium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kde.org/applications/education/minuet/&#34;&gt;Minuet&lt;/a&gt; brings a software for music education that teches students ear training, rhythm, harmony and more and provides features for teachers to create own lessons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning is also important for the youngest. &lt;a href=&#34;http://gcompris.net/&#34;&gt;Gcompris&lt;/a&gt; allows them to play and learn basics of a computer, elementary mathematics, geography, reading and many other things. Included are also games like puzzles, chess, memory and more that will make learning a pleasant and funny experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizing things is important, too. The Manjaro repository contains software like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/thunderbird/&#34;&gt;Thunderbird&lt;/a&gt; that provides an E-Mail client, a calendar and a news-reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To write homework or to create presentations, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.libreoffice.org/&#34;&gt;LibreOffice&lt;/a&gt; comes preinstalled.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>developers</title>
      <link>https://rumangerst.github.io/homepage/public/features/usercases/developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 15:08:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rumangerst.github.io/homepage/public/features/usercases/developers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Manjaro comes in many different edition, all with an unique workflow and user experience from a traditional desktop-environments to window-managers that are optimized for maximum performance and work efficience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system is set up easily, while giving developers all the freedom and space to tinker when wanted. All tools to compile and develop software are pre-installed. The integrated package-manager allows easy installation of IDE like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.qt.io/ide/&#34;&gt;Qt Creator&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kdevelop.org/&#34;&gt;KDevelop&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://netbeans.org/&#34;&gt;Netbeans&lt;/a&gt; and libraries like &lt;a href=&#34;http://libnoise.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;libnoise&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.boost.org/&#34;&gt;boost&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://matplotlib.org/&#34;&gt;matplotlib&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dependencies are automatically resolved and installing a library automatically install all needed headers to directly use it. Each edition comes preinstalled with powerful editors like &lt;a href=&#34;https://kate-editor.org/&#34;&gt;Kate&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.gnome.org/Apps/Gedit&#34;&gt;Gedit&lt;/a&gt;, while more editors like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&#34;&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.geany.org/&#34;&gt;Geany&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://bluefish.openoffice.nl/&#34;&gt;Bluefish&lt;/a&gt; are installed with one command or a few clicks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional to the repositories, Manjaro supports the Arch User Repository (AUR) that includes cutting-edge software and libraries, proprietary software like &lt;a href=&#34;https://unity3d.com/unity/editor&#34;&gt;Unity Editor&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yworks.com/products/yed&#34;&gt;yEd&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manjaro is a rolling-release distribution, which means that software is updated as soon as possible. This prevents lack of needed dependencies and old and buggy tool versions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>beginners</title>
      <link>https://rumangerst.github.io/homepage/public/features/usercases/beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 15:07:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rumangerst.github.io/homepage/public/features/usercases/beginners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Manjaro comes pre-installed with a collection of software that makes all-day tasks possible without even searching for them. If some application is not installed, more software can be easily and secure installed via the integrated package manager: Just search for &amp;ldquo;Office&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Music&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Internet&amp;rdquo;, say what should be installed and everything else will be done automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this software is also completely free and will be updated alongside with Manjaro. The Manjaro team and community will ensure that it will stay stable, safe and functions correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>artists</title>
      <link>https://rumangerst.github.io/homepage/public/features/usercases/artists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 15:07:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rumangerst.github.io/homepage/public/features/usercases/artists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Manjaro comes preinstalled with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gimp.org/&#34;&gt;GIMP&lt;/a&gt;, which is a very powerful image manipulation program. For drawing &lt;a href=&#34;https://krita.org/&#34;&gt;Krita&lt;/a&gt; will fulfill most of your needs, while &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.darktable.org/&#34;&gt;Darktable&lt;/a&gt; brings a top-notch and free photography suite. Vector-graphics can be done with programs such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://inkscape.org/&#34;&gt;Inkscape&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For simple or advanced video-editing, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kdenlive.org/&#34;&gt;Kdenlive&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openshot.org/&#34;&gt;OpenShot&lt;/a&gt; will do almost anything you need. There are also professional video-editing tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lwks.com/&#34;&gt;Lightworks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3D-Modelling can be done using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blender.org/&#34;&gt;Blender&lt;/a&gt;. Codecs for video and audio come pre-installed or are automatically fetched. Most of this software is completely free available and can be easily and secure installed by using Manjaro&amp;rsquo;s integrated package manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manjaro&amp;rsquo;s repositories also contain software useful for musicials such as the easy-to-use recording and editing software &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.audacityteam.org/&#34;&gt;Audacity&lt;/a&gt;. For more professional users &lt;a href=&#34;http://ardour.org/&#34;&gt;Ardour&lt;/a&gt; brings all the needed features. Sequencing, mixing and synthesizing can be done using &lt;a href=&#34;https://lmms.io/&#34;&gt;LMMS&lt;/a&gt;. Manjaro maintains &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.manjaro.org/t/a-realtime-kernel-for-manjaro/4066&#34;&gt;realtime&lt;/a&gt; versions of the Linux kernel that are designed for low latency and optimized for audio-engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful for everyone</title>
      <link>https://rumangerst.github.io/homepage/public/features/usercases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rumangerst.github.io/homepage/public/features/usercases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Manjaro is an efficient companion to serve your variety of needs and it is versatile to adapt to all of your needs. Our user base varies from newbies, students &amp;amp; teachers, programmers &amp;amp; developers, professionals, art enthusiast, music lovers, professional multimedia professionals and many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We asked our users why they use Manjaro and what software they use to relax, learn or do their work. You can find here a (by no means complete) list of software that is in most cases readily available via &lt;a href=&#34;;baseurl;features/tools#pamac&#34;&gt;the repositories&lt;/a&gt; without hunting them down in the internet and keeping watch that you won&amp;rsquo;t get malware.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fresh &amp; stable</title>
      <link>https://rumangerst.github.io/homepage/public/features/background/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 00:36:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rumangerst.github.io/homepage/public/features/background/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Manjaro based on the independently developed Arch operating system. Within the Linux community, Arch itself is renowned for being an exceptionally fast, powerful, and lightweight distribution that provides access to the very latest cutting edge – and bleeding edge – software. However, Arch is also aimed at more experienced or technically-minded users. As such, it is generally considered to be beyond the reach of those who lack the technical expertise (or persistence) required to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Latest software might come with some problems such as incompatibilities to existing software or bugs. Experienced users can fix those problems by themselves. But some users don&amp;rsquo;t have enough of this expertise or just don&amp;rsquo;t want to figure out how things actually work to get things working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To prevent problems, Manjaro adds additional layers of testing to the Arch repositories. Normal packages will go through this additional layers and will only be released for users who want a stable system, until no more problems are found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;;baseurl;/img/features/repositories.png&#34; alt=&#34;Manjaro repositories&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-security&#34;&gt;What about security?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As packages might be held back for weeks until all problems are resolved, the security of the system could be affected. Manjaro solves this by priotizing security-relevant packages in the testing process or even skipping the testing to make security-fixes as quickly available as possible. We call this process &lt;em&gt;fast-tracking&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>